Guide to the Dennis Cooper Papers ca. 1970-2002 MSS 085
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Oversize Materials Series VI: Little Caesar Magazine/Little Caesar Press
  - Subseries B: Little Caesar Press
    - Equi, Eline. Shrew Crazy. mockups, photos, artowrk, undated (Box 17, Folder 886)
    - Koertge, Ron. Diary Cows., undated (Box 17, Folder 887)
    - Gerard Malanga--mockups, undated (Box 17, Folder 889)
    - Gerstler, Amy. Yonder, undated (Box 17, Folder 890)
    - Gerstler, Amy, Yonder, undated (Box 17, Folder 891)
    - Lally, Michael. Hollywood Magic mockups, undated (Box 18, Folder 896)
    - Little Caesar Press photos, undated (Box 18, Folder 897)
    - Little Caesar Press posters, undated (Box 18, Folder 898)
    - Little Caesar Press, promotional material, undated (Box 18, Folder 899)
    - Rimbaud >77, undated (Box 18, Folder 907)
- Oversize Series VIII: Zines
  - Barsciet, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 925)
  - Chiappetta, Joe., 1991 (Box 19, Folder 930)
  - Dr. Smith. Toronto, Canada: Dr. Smith. June 1984 #1; Jul/Aug 1984 no2; Sept/Oct. 1994 no.3; Nov-Feb 1984-1985 no.4; Aug 1986 no.6; Fall-Winter 1986-1987 no.7, 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder 933)
  - Piss Elegant 1:1 and reissue. Public Enema no. 6 (1993), ca 1990-1993 (Box 19, Folder 934)
  - Ramrod New York: Ramrod. November 1990 1:3, December 1990 1:4, January 1991 1:5, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 956)
  - Sin Bros. Hollywood Ca: Sin Bros. Winter 1991 no. 5, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 959)
  - Tupor. Hamtramck, MI: Stupor. nos 3 and 5, undated (Box 19, Folder 964)
- Map Case
  - Series I Subseries A: Book Projects and Related Materials
    - Closer Press, undated (Folder 39A)
    - Frisk Promotional materials., undated (Folder 65A)
    - Horror Hospital unplugged, artwork., undated (Folder 110a)
  - Series I Subseries B: Book Projects and Related Materials
    - "Knife Tape Rope" Promotional posters, undated (Folder 195A)
    - "Them" promotional posters, undated (Folder 199A)
  - Series II:Book Projects and Correspondence of Writers and Artists
    - Kelley, Mike, undated (Folder 405A)
    - Gerstler, Amy and Benjamin Weissman "Read Out Loud", undated (Folder 344A)
    - Hawkins, Richard. Clippings, undated (Folder 371A)
    - Miller, Tim. Promotional materials, undated (Folder 438A)
  - Series IV: Biographical Material and Personal Correspondence. Subseries A: Biographical Material
    - Dennis Cooper reads at the Bop Shop, undated (Folder 782A)
    - Sound Off, undated (Folder 807A)
    - Performance Space 122. ACT-UP benefit., undated (Folder 812)
    - Miscellaneous Readings. Promotional posters, undated (Folder 825A)
  - Series VI: Little Caesar Magazine and Little Caesar Press. Subseries B: Little Caesar Press
    - "Coming Attractions" review, undated (Folder 882A)
- ACCRETION 2002 - Series I: Book projects and related materials
  - Subseries A: Book projects and related materials
    - Death and Sex File, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Death and Sex File, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Death and Sex File, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Death and Sex File, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Two Guys, manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Terror of Earrings, promotional flyer, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Safe, review by Peter Schjeldahl in VLS, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Frisk, film reviews/articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Frisk, review, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Frisk, interview with D. C. in Chemical Imbalance Magazine, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Frisk, "Framing the Gay Serial Killer: Dennis Cooper Off and On Screen," by Neil Hartlen, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Frisk/Try, Italian reviews/press, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Wrong, screenplay by Joseph Graham, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - A Herd, film treatment by David Collins, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Try, announcement in Grove New Fiction 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Try, film script (adapted by Sagheer Bin Faiz), undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Try, reviews/press, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Horror Hospital Unplugged, reviews/press, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Guide, early notes and drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Guide, image bank - Daniel Johns/Silverchair, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Guide, production notes (Grove), undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Guide, French Translation, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Guide, press/reviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Guide, press/reviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Guide, UK press/reviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Guide, French reviews/press, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - All Ears, rough manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - All Ears, reviews/promotional material, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Period, Lukas Haas, "Johns", undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Period, early drafts and notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Period, rough drafts and notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Period, draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Period, draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Period, draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Period, draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Period, draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Period, final draft with notes from editor, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Period, in type with edits, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Period, press/reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Period, press/reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 41a.)
    - Period, UK press/reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 41b.)
    - Notes/prompts for a talk on novel cycle, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Warm, porno screenplay, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - My Loose Thread, notes for mix tape (discarded storyline), undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - My Loose Thread, early draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - My Loose Thread, middle draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - My Loose Thread, late draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Subseries B: Book projects and related materials
    - The Freed Weed, promotional, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Brighten the Corners, reviews/promotional material, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Smallish, reviews/promotional material, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Guide To Trust #2, miscellaneous, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Subseries C: Collaborative Projects
    - Collaborations with Jane Eisenberg Dance Company, press/reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - St. Mark's Poetry Project, miscellaneous, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
- ACCRETION 2002 - Series II: Book Projects and Correspondence of Writers and Artists
  - Bachardy, Don, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Bellamy, Dodie & Kevin Killian, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Braithwaite, Lawrence, More at 7: 30 manuscript for Akashic Books project, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Cooper, Dennis to Matt Bailey, correspondence (1991-1994) (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Dlugos, Tim, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Equi, Elaine, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Fan Mail, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Fecteau, Vincent, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Gerstler, Amy, correspondence (early), undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Gerstler, Amy, correspondence (early), undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Gira, M., correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Glück, Robert, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Grauerholz, James W., correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Home, Stewart, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Indiana, Gary, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Jeppesen, Travis, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Jeppesen, Travis, "My Dead Face: A Story", undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Jeppesen, Travis, manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jeppesen, Travis, Victims manuscript for Akashic Books project, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Killian, Kevin, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Padgett, Ron, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Pera, Brian, "Bowery Boy" with cover letter, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Pera, Brian, "Mr. Charity", undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Pera, Brian, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Ray, Charles, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Sala, Jerome, correspondence (various poems), undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Sotos, Peter, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Stadler, Matthew, Allen Stein, early draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Stadler, Matthew, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Stark, Frances, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Taylor, Marvin, "A Dorian Gray Type of Thing: Male-Male Desire and the Crisis of Reproduction in Dennis Cooper's Closer. ", undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Terminator (JT Leroy), correspondence, photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Terminator (JT Leroy), draft of short story for Nerve, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Terminator (JT Leory), manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Trinidad, David, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Trinidad, David, student critiques of D. C. 's workshop and reading at Rutgers (includes article from Rutgers Daily Targum about D. C. 's reading), undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Trinidad, David and Ira Silverberg, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Wallace, David Foster, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Waller, Gavin, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Waters, John, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Welt, Bernard, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - White, Curtis, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Yamada, Sachiko, "Container," Japanese manga based on D. C. story, undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Let Palestinians build state: letter to Bay Area Reporter signed by D. C. and other queer writers., undated (Box 2, Folder 96a.)
- ACCRETION 2002 - Series III: Journalism [Includes Tearsheets of articles]
  - Artforum. Contributor profile, October 2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Artforum. Best of the '90s: Music, undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Artforum. Year 2000 Top Ten, undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Artforum. Best of 2001: Music, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Artforum. Real Life Rock: Dennis Cooper's Top Ten, undated (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Artforum. Review of Lars Von Trier's Dancer in the Dark, undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Artforum. Review of American Psycho Film, undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Artforum. First Communion (on Robert Bresson), undated (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Artforum. Odd Man Out (on David Wojnarowicz), undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Artforum. Dennis Cooper Talks with Mike Kelley, undated (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Artforum. On Nancy Burson, undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Artforum. On Jason Meadows, undated (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Artforum. On Amy Sarkisian, undated (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Artforum. On Frances Stark, undated (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Artforum. On Torbjorn Vejvi (published version, early draft with editorial suggestions), undated (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Artforum. Surf and Turf (article about UCLA's MFA program, featuring D. C. ), undated (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Bookforum. Review of Bad Girls and Sick Boys, undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Bookforum. Review of Jack Black's You Can't Win, undated (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Bookforum. Review of Fucked up and Photocopied, undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Bookforum. Review of Nick Drake: The Biography, undated (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Bookforum. Review of Harmony Korine's A Crack-up at the Race Riots, undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Bookforum. Review of Cookie Mueller's Ask Dr. Mueller, undated (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Bookforum. Bookforum Winter 2000, edited by Dennis Cooper, undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Fishwrap. Interview of Cooper, undated (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Frieze. On Torbjorn Vejvi, undated (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - GOSH! (early). It's a Small World: Los Angeles Poets, draft and published text, undated (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - GOSH! (early). It's a Small World: The Los Angeles Poetry Scene, draft and published text, undated (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - GOSH! (early). Los Angeles Bookfair, draft, undated (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - GOSH! (early). Gosh!, promotional material, undated (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - L. A. Weekly. L. A. Weekly edited by D. C., includes an interview with Clive Barker by D. C., undated (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - L. A. Weekly. Mystery Man, review of Denis Johnson's The Name of the World, undated (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - L. A. Weekly. Between the Lines: an Interview with Raymond Pettibon, undated (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - L. A. Weekly. Yobs to Men: The Scottish Lowlands of Irvine Welsh, undated (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Nest. Spooky House, undated (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Spin. On Alan Warner's The Sopranos, undated (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Spin. Got Poetry?, or why it matters in the age of Jewel, undated (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Spin. Dope Books: The Ups and Downs of Drugged-out Fiction, undated (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Time Out NY. Interview with Brad Renfro, undated (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Village Voice. Tom Spanbaur's Journey from Margin to Center, undated (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Village Voice. Nocturnal Emotions, interview with Jane Mendelsohn, undated (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Voice Literary Supplement. Abjection Overruled, Spring 1997 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Early Journalism. Philip Brandes: Screenwriter, undated (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Early Journalism. The Punk Press, undated (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Early Journalism. Review of Tom Clark's When Things Get Tough on Easy Street, undated (Box 3, Folder 140)
- ACCRETION 2002 - Series IV: Biographical material and personal correspondence.
  - Subseries A: Biographical material
    - Juvenalia, early 1960s and 1970s poetry, etc., ca. 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Juvenalia, late 1960s poetry, ca. 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Juvenalia, late 1960s poetry, ca. 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Juvenalia, 1966 school essays and stories (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Juvenalia, writing for school, undated (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Juvenalia, 1968 poetry and art (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Juvenalia, Napili, poetry, n. d., undated (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Juvenalia, 1968 "I Hate," novel (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Juvenalia, 1968 The Adventures of T. H. I. S. Clunk, novel (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Juvenalia, 1968-1969 "Trapped in My Armour," poetry (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Juvenalia, 1968-1970 poetry (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Juvenalia, 1968-1970 novel attempt (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Juvenalia, 1968-1973 poetry, prose, art (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Juvenalia, Motif '69, magazine, undated (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Juvenalia, 1969, Aillusionary Fungus, Flintridge Prep Literary Magazine (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Juvenalia, 1969 "... and I'll Beat You in the Morning," play (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Juvenalia, 1969-1970 poetry and correspondence (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Juvenalia, 1970 "The Human Lawnmower," poetry (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Juvenalia, 1970-1971 "To My Captain," poetry (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Juvenalia, 1970-1971 "This Life," poetry (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Juvenalia, 1971 "Of Changes," poetry (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Juvenalia, 1971-1972, poetry (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Juvenalia, 1972-1973, diary and poetry (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Juvenalia, 1973 poetry, etc. (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - He Cried: Novelist Dennis Cooper Hits Home, L. A. Weekly, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Writing About Dennis Cooper's Work, Misc., undated (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Bibliographic Checklist of North American Enghlish-language Gay Poets 1900-1990 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Conversations with Gay Novelists, interview/correspondence with Richard Canning, undated (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Combustible Romanticism, Interview with D. C. by Brandon Stosuy, undated (Box 4, Folder 170)
- ACCRETION 2002 - Series VII: Media Material
  - Subseries B: Videotapes (Readings) - Original Material
    Access copies for this material may not be available. See Series VII Subseries A: Video Recordings - Access Copies.
    - More Than a Mouthful #37 w/ Dennis Cooper and Eileen Myles (VHS), undated (Box 4, Folder ID: 085.0015)
  - Subseries C: Videos (Research) - Original Material
    - Frontline PBS: The Killer At Thurston High School (VHS) ["Kip Kinkel" - inspiration My Loose Thread], undated (Box 4, Folder ID: 085.0016)
- ACCRETION 2002 - Series IX: Posters
  - Prose Acts Broadsides - paragraph from My Loose Thread, signed by D. C. (1 in edition of 26) & unsigned copy (unnumbered in edition of 40), undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
- Oversize Materials ACCRETION 2002 - Series I: Book Projects and Related Materials
  - Subseries A: Book Projects and related materials
    - Guide, miscellaneous research materials, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Period. Wooden house box inscribed "PERIOD". Inside, color slides of Vincent Fecteau's artwork ranging in dates from 1994-1999. Color printer copy of a house. Color photographs of carnival including buildings, rides, backstage and props. Magazine photograph of a young man. Period diagram and letter, text scribbled out, still legible., undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
- Oversize Materials ACCRETION 2002 Series IV:Biographical Material and Personal Correspondence
  - Subseries A: Biographical Material
    - Journal/Scrapbook regarding "Ideal Beauty" (1993-95), 1993-1995 (Box 19, Folder 166)